<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<items>

	<item  id="train-logs-8">
		<date>
			<year>2016</year>
			<month>11</month>
			<day>22</day>
		</date>
		<title>Train Logs #8 - 22/11/2016 12:11 pm</title>
		<text>	
		We are on track (pun intended) to reach Haripur close to the thirty hour mark, same as last time.
		&lt;br&gt;We've just left Rawalpindi.
		&lt;br&gt;One thing I will admit is better about Karachi than Haripur is the lack of dry skin. Haripur and surrounding areas of similar climate are killer for the skin in winter, particularly if you have a dry skin.
		I already have dry patches on my skin and lips and I have yet to bring water into the mix.
		&lt;br&gt;In less than two hours we will be in Haripur. I am as giddy as a schoolboy on the final day before spring break.
		&lt;br&gt;This blog has been a handy pastime but now it has to die. Its memories will serve as warning to future daredevils thinking of taking this plunge.
		&lt;br&gt;Here be dragons. Peace Out! 		
		</text>
		<keywords>
			<keyword>train</keyword>
			<keyword>logs</keyword>
			<keyword>log</keyword>
			<keyword>rail</keyword>
			<keyword>railway</keyword>
			<keyword>writing</keyword>
			<keyword>travel</keyword>
			<keyword>karachi</keyword>
			<keyword>haripur</keyword>
			<keyword>8</keyword>
			<keyword>eight</keyword>	
		</keywords>
	</item>

	<item  id="train-logs-7">
		<date>
			<year>2016</year>
			<month>11</month>
			<day>21</day>
		</date>
		<title>Train Logs #7 - 21/11/2016 2:10 pm</title>
		<text>	
		&lt;div class='code urdu'&gt;
		نشانِ راہ ہے بچی کا صبر، حوصلہ اس کا کمال
		&lt;br&gt;
		شکوہ جائے پھسل ، کیا ہے اس کی مجال
		&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
		کیا بھلا عمر ہے  توقیر کے اس پیکر کی
		&lt;br&gt;
		فرق اک دو برس کے سے ہو گی قریباًست سال
		&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
		فکر کرتی ہے سدا شیطان کے اُس چیلے کی
		&lt;br&gt;
		سراپا بڑی بہن کا ہے، پہرہ دارِ اطفال
		&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
		پھر بھی سنتی ہے ملات کہ ہے لڑکی وہ
		&lt;br&gt;
		محوِ حیرت ہوں کہ موجود ہیں یہ طرز، یہ اخیال
		&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
		ہمت و حوصلہ کیا پختون کی فطرت ثانی ہے؟
		&lt;br&gt;
		اِ س کے سچ ہونے کی تصدیق ہیں یہ احوال
		&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
		اذیت انگیز سواری ، یہ مسافت، یہ سفر، لیکن
		&lt;br&gt;
		ایک پل طاری ہونے نہ دیا اضمحلال
		&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
		سعد کا دل جب کبھی بیچ میں بیزار ہوا
		&lt;br&gt;
		پا لیا پھر سے سکوں دیکھ کہ اس کی مثال
		&lt;/div&gt;

		&lt;br&gt;From the ashes a fire shall be woken,
		&lt;br&gt;A light from the shadows shall spring

		&lt;br&gt;I have always wanted to write a full poem, anything more than two verses at a time. However, writing a poem is a boring and long undertaking that I was unwilling to to take. So far my forays into poetry haven been short and are usually written when I am bored out of my mind.
		&lt;br&gt;On the journey to Karachi, the family sitting next to us was a Pakhtun family. There was a girl of about seven that caught my attention. The resolve and maturity she demonstrated was well beyond her years. I wanted to write about her in one of my entries but what I wanted to write would come across as ridiculous and over the top. On the journey home I decided instead to write a poem on the girl. Since poetry is a format that welcomes the ridiculous, the over the top, and the exaggerated, the subject matter would lend itself well to poetry.
		&lt;br&gt;Long story short, and I realize as I write this that that ship has already sailed, I wrote my first full poem. I have known for sometime that I am at my creative best when I'm bored, so as to eliminate the boredom. All I have got to do now is to be bored at all times.
		&lt;br&gt;Ugh! Excuse me, I have got to go vomit at the thought.	
		</text>
		<keywords>
			<keyword>train</keyword>
			<keyword>logs</keyword>
			<keyword>log</keyword>
			<keyword>rail</keyword>
			<keyword>railway</keyword>
			<keyword>writing</keyword>
			<keyword>travel</keyword>
			<keyword>karachi</keyword>
			<keyword>haripur</keyword>
			<keyword>7</keyword>
			<keyword>seven</keyword>	
		</keywords>
	</item>

	<item  id="train-logs-6">
		<date>
			<year>2016</year>
			<month>11</month>
			<day>21</day>
		</date>
		<title>Train Logs #6 - 21/11/2016 9:39 pm</title>
		<text>	
		I read somewhere that the journey home is always easier. I can't remember where I read it but I have always found that my experience affirms the statement.
		&lt;br&gt;We started on the return journey today at 6:15 in the morning. Just two days of Karachi's water has turned my stomach upside down. I have found through repeated painful experiences in the past that Lahore's water does not agree with me. Apparently the same the same is true for Karachi. Of course my over consumption in the last two meals couldn't have helped matters.
		&lt;br&gt;Already, the journey seems easier, there is a nip in the air and the world seems brighter. We'll see how long that lasts.
		&lt;br&gt;We saw more of Karachi yesterday then I could have ever hoped because of our host, Rana Akram. An old friend of my father's, he is one of the most interesting people I have ever met. So interesting and charismatic is he in fact that I was able to ignore his constant barbs at Haripur, as well as overcome my crippling  social ineptness and talk with him like I do not remember doing with a new acquaintance. From what I could gather during my brief time with him, he seems to lack, and I say that with utmost respect, the filter between his thoughts and speech that most of us rigorously employ. This makes for very interesting and entertaining conversations where he constantly dishes out judgments only to play down his statements moments later.
		&lt;br&gt;I do not understand all the negative press that Karachi gets. Despite the obvious problems it was still one of the most enchanting place I've ever visited (which is admittedly not a long list). The perfect blend of modern and historic architecture and infrastructure.	
		</text>
		<keywords>
			<keyword>train</keyword>
			<keyword>logs</keyword>
			<keyword>log</keyword>
			<keyword>rail</keyword>
			<keyword>railway</keyword>
			<keyword>writing</keyword>
			<keyword>travel</keyword>
			<keyword>karachi</keyword>
			<keyword>haripur</keyword>
			<keyword>6</keyword>
			<keyword>six</keyword>	
		</keywords>
	</item>

	<item  id="train-logs-5">
		<date>
			<year>2016</year>
			<month>11</month>
			<day>18</day>
		</date>
		<title>Train Logs #5 - 18/11/2016 11:40 pm</title>
		<text>	
		Shockingly the train reached Karachi only one hour behind schedule. I guess we should count our lucky stars. The entire journey lasted for about thirty two hours.
		&lt;br&gt;Karachi looks better than I expected. In the back of my mind the thought of the journey back looms like a shadow.
		&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
		Let's never do this again.	
		</text>
		<keywords>
			<keyword>train</keyword>
			<keyword>logs</keyword>
			<keyword>log</keyword>
			<keyword>rail</keyword>
			<keyword>railway</keyword>
			<keyword>writing</keyword>
			<keyword>travel</keyword>
			<keyword>karachi</keyword>
			<keyword>haripur</keyword>
			<keyword>5</keyword>
			<keyword>five</keyword>	
		</keywords>
	</item>

	<item  id="train-logs-4">
		<date>
			<year>2016</year>
			<month>11</month>
			<day>18</day>
		</date>
		<title>Train Logs #4 - 18/11/2016 11:42 am</title>
		<text>	
		Sindh: What a shithole.
		&lt;br&gt;I can not imagine a more desolate yet fertile area. Maybe it's the two month drought doing its magic. but so far the entire area seems to be ground zero to Operation Dust Storm. The green has a gloomy yellow tint to it. The same is true for everything else.
		&lt;br&gt;It is dawning on me that the weird yellow filter most Hollywood movies and TV shows use when representing Pakistan as well as most of Middle East and South Asia may not simply be ignorance and bias. Maybe their only experience of Pakistan is this wretched piece of land and the rest of the country just got lumped together with it. Like civilians in a cross-fire.
		&lt;br&gt;My alter-ego remains staunch and resolute, let's see if he can keep it up.
		</text>
		<keywords>
			<keyword>train</keyword>
			<keyword>logs</keyword>
			<keyword>log</keyword>
			<keyword>rail</keyword>
			<keyword>railway</keyword>
			<keyword>writing</keyword>
			<keyword>travel</keyword>
			<keyword>karachi</keyword>
			<keyword>haripur</keyword>
			<keyword>4</keyword>
			<keyword>four</keyword>	
		</keywords>
	</item>

	<item  id="train-logs-3">
		<date>
			<year>2016</year>
			<month>11</month>
			<day>18</day>
		</date>
		<title>Train Logs #3 - 18/11/2016 8:10 am</title>
		<text>	
		&lt;br&gt;The night passed like a blur. I woke up a lot between short spans of sleep. Altogether it wasn't particularly discomforting.
		&lt;br&gt;I had to go to the bathroom earlier tomorrow. I hate unfamiliar bathrooms; especially the public ones. I haven't eaten much since the start of the journey. I normally reduce food and fluid intake to a bare minimum when traveling to avoid unnecessary visits to the unfancied. I knew I would have to go once, I am determined to keep it to one.
		&lt;br&gt;We still haven't managed to leave Punjab. There are twelve more hours ahead of us, if we are lucky.I prefer the daytime, it isn't cold and the unending plains of green are relaxing.
		&lt;br&gt;We've reached Bahawalpur, I've gotta go.
		</text>
		<keywords>
			<keyword>train</keyword>
			<keyword>logs</keyword>
			<keyword>log</keyword>
			<keyword>rail</keyword>
			<keyword>railway</keyword>
			<keyword>writing</keyword>
			<keyword>travel</keyword>
			<keyword>karachi</keyword>
			<keyword>haripur</keyword>
			<keyword>3</keyword>
			<keyword>three</keyword>	
		</keywords>
	</item>

	<item  id="train-logs-2">
		<date>
			<year>2016</year>
			<month>11</month>
			<day>17</day>
		</date>
		<title>Train Logs #2 - 17/11/2016 9:35 pm</title>
		<text>	
		Seven hours in and it hasn't been as bad as I imagined it would be. Then again, it never is. I have a pessimistic imagination.
		&lt;br&gt;For the most part it's been dull and mildly uncomfortable. I maybe the second laziest person I know, but when thrown into an unwanted situation I usually turn into a completely different person. That person is hopelessly cheerful and active, and he has a rather adventurous personality.
		&lt;br&gt;I have an ominous feelings that the worst is yet to come. Actually when you consider the fact that we have still about twenty four hours (if we are very lucky) to go it's not something as subtle as a feeling so much as it is a giant neon sign announcing bad things to come.
		&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;As Anaking Skywalker said: "This is where the fun begins".
		</text>
		<keywords>
			<keyword>train</keyword>
			<keyword>logs</keyword>
			<keyword>log</keyword>
			<keyword>rail</keyword>
			<keyword>railway</keyword>
			<keyword>writing</keyword>
			<keyword>travel</keyword>
			<keyword>karachi</keyword>
			<keyword>haripur</keyword>
			<keyword>2</keyword>
			<keyword>two</keyword>	
		</keywords>
	</item>	

	<item  id="train-logs-1">
		<date>
			<year>2016</year>
			<month>11</month>
			<day>17</day>
		</date>
		<title>Train Logs #1 - 17/11/2016 2:37 pm</title>
		<text>	
		I have to go to Karachi. Due to a sudden change of plans, I had to book a last minute ticket with my brother and mother on the Hazara Express, the crown jewel of the ever increasingly shitty Pakistan Railway. The journey is scheduled for thirty one hours from Haripur to Karachi, although as anyone who is even remotely familiar with this fine organization would know, that means at least thirty five hours. I am keeping a log of the journey to pass the time. The last minute booking means that I do not have a berth booked. Needless to say this can be an interesting read.
		&lt;br&gt;I have professed my hatred of traveling one of my blogs before, so as you may be able to imagine, this worst of journeys under the worst of circumstances is nature at its cruelest for me.
		&lt;br&gt;As soon as I entered the compartment, the strong odor emanating from what I hope is the bathroom hits me like a punch. I move in and find that I have to be content with the side seat. The whole compartment smells vaguely of vomit.
		&lt;br&gt;I am already sick of this journey.	
		</text>
		<keywords>
			<keyword>train</keyword>
			<keyword>logs</keyword>
			<keyword>log</keyword>
			<keyword>rail</keyword>
			<keyword>railway</keyword>
			<keyword>writing</keyword>
			<keyword>travel</keyword>
			<keyword>karachi</keyword>
			<keyword>haripur</keyword>	
			<keyword>1</keyword>
			<keyword>one</keyword>
		</keywords>
	</item>	

	<item  id="classroom-thoughts-12">
		<date>
			<year>2016</year>
			<month>11</month>
			<day>09</day>
		</date>
		<title>Classroom Thoughts #12</title>
		<text>	
		I haven't written anything in quite sometime. Up until today, even the most potent of catalysts could not motivate me to put pen to paper. When I say "the most potent of catalysts" I speak of course of the severe episodes of boredom that are triggered by the astoundingly dull classes.
		&lt;br&gt;
		The reason for this "writer" 's block is my inability to come up with a ridiculous or humorous premise to write about. I am mortally incapable of putting two sentences together without making a joke. I love reading, and I love writing, and I would love to write a long story, but writing a story requires you to take your writing seriously, something I just can not do. If I try to write a serious story or even try envisioning myself writing one, I cringe so hard that I cramp all the muscles in my body, making me both mentally &lt;i&gt;and&lt;/i&gt; physically incapable of following through.
		&lt;br&gt;
		Even as I write this, I have half a mind to scrap this and just endure the class. Speaking of which, it seems somebody cranked up the boredom to eleven today. The teachers keep topping each other. It's nice see such spirit of one-upmanship.
		</text>
		<keywords>
			<keyword>classroom</keyword>
			<keyword>thougths</keyword>
			<keyword>class</keyword>
			<keyword>bored</keyword>
			<keyword>humor</keyword>
			<keyword>writing</keyword>
			<keyword>teacher</keyword>
			<keyword>block</keyword>
			<keyword>boredom</keyword>		
		</keywords>
	</item>   
	<item  id="there-and-back-again">
		<date>
			<year>2016</year>
			<month>07</month>
			<day>25</day>
		</date>
		<title>There and back again</title>
		<text>	
		I have been away from the blog for three months. The decision to take this hiatus stemmed from a desire to do better academically (about time really). Things didn't entirely go according to plan, but if I'm being honest with my self they went better than I expected. I got some work done, and even worked on quite a few assignments and a project or two.
		&lt;br&gt;I came, I saw, I mildly surprised myself.
		&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;In other news I am going through a full blown episode of football withdrawal as July comes to a close.
		&lt;br&gt;The life of a football fan has it's highs and lows. Most of these lows roll around during the breaks, whether they be summer, winter or international breaks. Why do these footballers need so many breaks is beyond me. They are getting paid fortunes to play football, something most people would consider the best vacation ever.
		&lt;br&gt;I, for one, can not wait til the robots take over, specifically because then we can have robot footballers who won't need any breaks. Football all year long! it will make the life in slavery of the machine overlords much easier
		&lt;br&gt;Another reason to want the season to get underway as soon as possible is to get away from the transfer window. I feel the statement can be justifiably explained by stating a simple fact. I am an Arsenal fan. 'Nuff said.	</text>
		<keywords>
			<keyword>there</keyword>
			<keyword>and</keyword>
			<keyword>back</keyword>
			<keyword>again</keyword>
			<keyword>there and back again</keyword>
			<keyword>writing</keyword>
			<keyword>football</keyword>
			<keyword>arsenal</keyword>
			<keyword>withdrawal</keyword>		
			<keyword>robot</keyword>
			<keyword>robots</keyword>
			<keyword>takeover</keyword>
		</keywords>
	</item> 
 
	<item  id="classroom-thoughts-11">
		<date>
			<year>2016</year>
			<month>04</month>
			<day>19</day>
		</date>
		<title>Classroom Thoughts #11</title>
		<text>	
		The "Classroom Thoughts" series is being put on hold for the foreseeable future. The decision to put this series, and as an extension the blog, on ice is one that we feel was necessary if we are to achieve the goals and objectives of this organization. This marks a paradigm shift, a priority change in the short term strategy and objectives of the company.
		&lt;br&gt;The whole team is saddened to say goodby, albeit only for the time being, to the very beloved, lighthearted and lightheaded writing, that we have so immensely enjoyed writing over the years. This has been an extremely adventurous and entertaining ride, yet we look forward to actually getting some work done for a change.
		&lt;br&gt;We leave you on a high note with the following gem courtesy of J.R.R. Tolkien, which we have been waiting for ages to plug into the blog:
		&lt;div class='code'&gt;
			From the ashes a fire shall be woken,
		&lt;br&gt;    A light from the shadows shall spring;
		&lt;br&gt;    Renewed shall be blade that was broken,
		&lt;br&gt;    The crownless again shall be king
		&lt;/div&gt;
		&lt;em&gt;This was a public service message by the probably brain damaged and most certainly sleep deprived people(s?) at Saad Khan.&lt;/em&gt;
		</text>
		<keywords>
			<keyword>clssroom</keyword>
			<keyword>thougths</keyword>
			<keyword>09</keyword>
			<keyword>9</keyword>
			<keyword>number</keyword>
			<keyword>writing</keyword>
			<keyword>bored</keyword>
			<keyword>university</keyword>
			<keyword>class</keyword>
			<keyword>bus</keyword>
			<keyword>hate</keyword>
			<keyword>ride</keyword>
			<keyword>pain</keyword>
			<keyword>commute</keyword>
			<keyword>travel</keyword>
			<keyword>classroom thoughts</keyword>
		</keywords>
	</item> 
 
	<item  id="classroom-thoughts-10">
		<date>
			<year>2016</year>
			<month>04</month>
			<day>07</day>
		</date>
		<title>Classroom Thoughts #10: 2-1</title>
		<text>	
		El Clásico, or the Classic, is the name given to the Barcelona vs Real Madrid match. Watched by hundred of millions around the world, this game is about much more than just the three points, or winning or losing. This game is about bragging rights, and the losing side and their fans feel the sting of the loss as long as they don't avenge it. The match means the world to the fans the world over, and losing this encounter can be particularly hard to take, and it can knock the stuffing out of the team spirit.
		&lt;br&gt;The last Clásico, played this week, resulted in a 2-1 loss to Barcelona. The loss was especially tough to handle given the form of the two teams, as well as the fact that Barça blew away a 1-0 lead to lose against a 10 men Real. I have decided to write out a few things that help me swallow this bitter pill, and have helped me through dark times like these in the past. So here is my &lt;s&gt; one&lt;/s&gt; five point formula for feeling better.
		&lt;br&gt;&lt;s&gt;1. Stop watching football, or at least stop supporting any club. If you do not take any side, you can not get hurt. &lt;/s&gt;
		&lt;br&gt;1. Play FIFA. In the past, I have found the football simulation game to be surprisingly therapeutic in dealing with a frustrating result. Crushing a team 5-0 while keeping 70% of possession is great stress relief.
		&lt;br&gt;2. Focus you attention on other things. Distract yourself from thinking about the game, by doing anything that you can think of. This could be anything, as mundane as writing a how-to on getting over the defeat or simply remembering the 4-0 thrashing dealt to Real by Barcelona the last time out.
		&lt;br&gt;3. Remind yourself: It's just a game. Tell this to yourself till you start believing it, which admittedly, may take some time. It's not the end of the world, the game goes on. As the cliché goes, it's part and parcel of the game.
		&lt;br&gt; 4. Read up on the rants of fellow fans on internet forums. Reading other people vent out their frustration will be a sobering experience, reminding you that you are not alone in feeling the pain. If you really need a release, go ahead and let it all out, it's is a safe space where everybody would be sympathetic and understanding.
		&lt;br&gt;I have to warn about the choice of the platform though, as it can enrage you further to read the "fans" if you go to the wrong place, which really is the opposite of what we're going for here. I have found the team's individual sub-reddits on reddit to be more mature and level headed than most places on the internet. Granted, that is not saying a lot since the bar is so low, but you may find something to be better than nothing.
		&lt;br&gt;5. Whatever you do, &lt;i&gt;do not&lt;/i&gt; try to blame the referee or talk smack about the opposition player's behavior and how they didn't deserve to win.
		&lt;br&gt;For the first point, most of the time, the referee does not decide the game. The referee make mistakes every game, La Liga refs more so than the others, and you should not be using that as a shield against criticism for the team. Snap out of the victim complex, the authorities &lt;i&gt;do not&lt;/i&gt; have it in for your team.
		&lt;br&gt;For the second point, each team has players with attitude issues and bad habits. Get off the high horse, your club is not much better than theirs in morality and values. Unless the other club is Chelsea, in which case, keep on hatin', my good man. But on a serious note, just don't do these. You look petty and it does nothing for you or the team.
		&lt;br&gt;I wrote this blog semi-seriously, which, come to think of it is exactly like everything else I've ever written, but doing the above actually &lt;i&gt;has&lt;/i&gt; helped me deal with disappointment. I believe it can be helpful to everyone, regardless of their team affiliations. That is, everyone apart from Arsenal and Liverpool fans. How can anything help you feel better if you keep putting yourself through that, you clearly like getting hurt, you piece of work!
		</text>
		<keywords>
			<keyword>clssroom</keyword>
			<keyword>thougths</keyword>
			<keyword>09</keyword>
			<keyword>9</keyword>
			<keyword>number</keyword>
			<keyword>writing</keyword>
			<keyword>bored</keyword>
			<keyword>university</keyword>
			<keyword>class</keyword>
			<keyword>bus</keyword>
			<keyword>hate</keyword>
			<keyword>ride</keyword>
			<keyword>pain</keyword>
			<keyword>commute</keyword>
			<keyword>travel</keyword>
			<keyword>classroom thoughts</keyword>
		</keywords>
	</item> 
  
	<item  id="classroom-thoughts-09">
		<date>
			<year>2016</year>
			<month>04</month>
			<day>06</day>
		</date>
		<title>Classroom Thoughts #09</title>
		<text>	
		If you think you know pain, you may want to reconsider that after you are done reading this. The following writing may be disturbing and contains graphic detail, reader discretion is advised, so proceed at your own peril.
		&lt;br&gt;I have expressed my love of the bus ride to  the university a few times before this, but today I will go into all the gory details of this charade of a bus ride. For maximum visualization, I will put you in my shoes.
		&lt;br&gt;You have to get to the university early each day to attend the first class, so you wake up early, 6AM at the very latest. After shoveling down the hastily prepared breakfast, you trot, or jog depending on the time, down to the bus stop at 7AM. You wait for the bus and keep a weather eye on the horizon for the dust storm that preludes the bus's arrival. The bus slows down long enough for you to hop aboard and you are a go.
		&lt;br&gt;Now for the fun part, you begin seat hunting, hoping that luck will be on your side, and that your sides will not be aching from standing up for half of the hour and a half journey. Standing up is particularly problematic when you are 6'2" and you have to crane your neck down just to make sure your head does not  bump against the roof of the bus, which can be quite painful what with the decor and the sharp edges of the stylized terrain of the roof.
		&lt;br&gt;
		&lt;img src='blog/bus.jpg' alt='Bowser Bus'&gt; &lt;div class='caption'&gt;Pictured: Either a bus doing it's best Bowser impression, or Bowser doing his best bus impression.&lt;/div&gt;
		&lt;br&gt;If you do find a seat, you will have to see if you can actually set yourself down on it, which can be tricky because many of the seats have inadequate space for the legs and being unable to detach your legs at command, you have but two options: either to sit down and force your knees through a world of pain, or keep standing and make your knees go through a world of pain on the bumpy road. There really is no win scenario here. And if, God forbid, you are the third man in a three person seat, you will have the best of the both worlds, as half of you will be sitting down while the other half dangles down, hanging on for dear life. The lack of empathy that the people demonstrate for the simplest niceties in the society astounds me. What really angers me is that if I, being a hunk of a man, can manage to stay within the confines of my one third of the seat, how can these people be so socially irresponsible so as to make life miserable for others, especially when it is so easily avoidable for their skinny selves. I found it hilarious that there is a word in English for this, the word being "man spreading". So elegant, so accurate, I suddenly find myself hating English a little less.
		&lt;br&gt;Whether you are sitting or standing, does not make much difference in the blistering heat of the Haripur summer. Drenched in sweat, jumping and flailing across the bus because of the bumpy ride, all notions of minding the gap forgotten in the great mass of humanity which keeps on piling up as the conductor refuses to lose a single passenger, bathing in the dust that covers the bus, you would know pain as you have not known before.
		&lt;br&gt;On the really fun days, you may even get to ride atop the bus, owing to the lack of space inside of it, and if this happens on a winter morning, well, you are in for a bumpy ride, both literally and figuratively.
		&lt;br&gt;Whenever I'm feeling really down, I like to recall these joy rides and ask myself, if that couldn't break me, what can? Works like a charm every time. Whoever said fortune favors the brave  better be right though, because keeping up this routine is taking every ounce of bravery and persistence I've got.
		</text>
		<keywords>
			<keyword>clssroom</keyword>
			<keyword>thougths</keyword>
			<keyword>09</keyword>
			<keyword>9</keyword>
			<keyword>number</keyword>
			<keyword>writing</keyword>
			<keyword>bored</keyword>
			<keyword>university</keyword>
			<keyword>class</keyword>
			<keyword>bus</keyword>
			<keyword>hate</keyword>
			<keyword>ride</keyword>
			<keyword>pain</keyword>
			<keyword>commute</keyword>
			<keyword>travel</keyword>
			<keyword>classroom thoughts</keyword>
		</keywords>
	</item> 

	<item  id="classroom-thoughts-08">
		<date>
			<year>2016</year>
			<month>04</month>
			<day>02</day>
		</date>
		<title>Classroom Thoughts #08: Rain Blues</title>
		<text>	
		I hate rain. 
		&lt;br&gt;When I say that, I don't mean a I-would-prefer-if-it-didn't dislike, but a degree of hate only describable as irrational.
		&lt;br&gt;I was raised in a conservative and deeply religious household, as a result I do not use profanities, ever. Though I am usually proud of this and see no reason to dabble in swearing, there &lt;em&gt;are&lt;/em&gt; a few things that make me want to swear out loud. These things include people on public transport who take up too much space and make those sitting next to them miserable, then there are people who try to deliberately hurt others while playing football. Nothing, however, makes me want to bleeping bleep as badly and as furiously as rain.
		&lt;br&gt;Having already characterized my hate as irrational, I will try to make sense of the nonsense and understand my loathing of the rain. If I think about it, it becomes quite clear that rain dampens, pun unapologetically intended, my spirits because it puts a stop to everything I love to do. It literally is the rain on my parade, again I regret nothing.
		&lt;br&gt; I love playing football, and though the rain shouldn't theoretically stop me from playing, in reality, the pitch I play on is a mess, and the rain turns it into a mud bath waiting to happen. Everything, apart from football, that I love to do, involves my computer, and rain in my area means an almost guaranteed blackout. The people in charge of providing and maintaining electricity would rather let the entire population be drowned in darkness, than having to fix the damage on the off chance of an electric shortage.
		&lt;br&gt;The lack of electricity also means that the hours after the dark have to be spent sitting in a room, staring into the abyss, while trying to figure out something fun to talk about.
		&lt;br&gt;And if that wasn't enough reason to bang my head against the wall and wish an eternity of pain on the rain, I also happen to live in a place that was most likely built by the Aryans when they first entered India. If you don't see where this is going, I envy you. A couple of days of relentless rain, turn the ceiling of the house into a shower, and the one cozy place you call home turns into a wet, smelly nightmare, making me wish I could curl up into my bed and die, or at the very least pass out until the sun comes out.
		&lt;br&gt;Writing this out made me realize my hate of rain is not irrational or uncalled for at all, but is as reasonable as any hate can get.
		&lt;br&gt;
		&lt;br&gt;I hate you rain! May you burn in the everlasting flames of hell, if only to vaporize all the water that is the reason for my misery.
		</text>
		<keywords>
			<keyword>clssroom</keyword>
			<keyword>thougths</keyword>
			<keyword>08</keyword>
			<keyword>8</keyword>
			<keyword>number</keyword>
			<keyword>writing</keyword>
			<keyword>bored</keyword>
			<keyword>university</keyword>
			<keyword>class</keyword>
			<keyword>rain</keyword>
			<keyword>hate</keyword>
			<keyword>angry</keyword>
			<keyword>classroom thoughts</keyword>
		</keywords>
	</item> 
  
	<item  id="classroom-thoughts-07">
		<date>
			<year>2016</year>
			<month>04</month>
			<day>02</day>
		</date>
		<title>Classroom Thoughts #07</title>
		<text>	
		Growing up, me and my brothers played many game that I would like to think not many other children play, or at least not with the level of detail and dedication that we did.
		&lt;br&gt;I have decided to write them down before I forget them, partly or completely, either naturally, or through head-injury induced amnesia, the probability of which has increased substantially since I started playing football.
		&lt;br&gt;The earliest game I remember playing, is something we used to call, simply "&lt;span class="urdu"&gt; خفیہ &lt;/span&gt;", which translates to "Secret". We took the name extremely seriously, so much so that to this day, not even my mother knows exactly what it was we used to do all day long for about five years. Now, for obvious reasons, I would not be divulging the details of the game. I am willing to take those details to the grave, or to loose them  along the way.
		&lt;br&gt;We used to have a storyline that spanned about half a century, characters that we were extremely protective of, a king, enemies that we used to fight (usually by taking our wooden "swords" to town on the shrubs and weeds outside the house). We kept meticulous record of the many factions and of all the characters that made up those factions. Some of these records have survived the test of time, and are a living example of our awesomeness.
		&lt;br&gt;We had four factions within our kingdom, one for each stakeholder, made up of me, two of my brothers and a cousin. The other siblings and cousins knew as much about it like the rest of the world, that is to say nothing at all.
		</text>
		<keywords>
			<keyword>clssroom</keyword>
			<keyword>thougths</keyword>
			<keyword>07</keyword>
			<keyword>7</keyword>
			<keyword>number</keyword>
			<keyword>writing</keyword>
			<keyword>bored</keyword>
			<keyword>university</keyword>
			<keyword>class</keyword>
			<keyword>game</keyword>
			<keyword>childhood</keyword>
			<keyword>khufia</keyword>
			<keyword>abdullah</keyword>
			<keyword>ibraheem</keyword>
			<keyword>LARPing</keyword>
			<keyword>classroom thoughts</keyword>
		</keywords>
	</item> 
 
	<item  id="classroom-thoughts-06">
		<date>
			<year>2016</year>
			<month>04</month>
			<day>01</day>
		</date>
		<title>Classroom Thoughts #06</title>
		<text>	
		I have been writing a lot these past two weeks, and most of these writing are bland, boring, and generic. The classes have pushed me down a rabbit hole, and I have found to, to my horror, the most boring wonderland anybody could've ever imagined.
		&lt;br&gt;This is particularly unsettling for me because I absolutely despise writing anything even remotely serious. I have grudgingly decided to write them and continue writing them, because, as I said in the last entry, I am trying to get better, and to cast the fear (and disgust) aside.
		&lt;br&gt;As I read what I have written here so far, I realize that I have done it again. To remedy this, I tried to write a joke about the slump that Arsenal, my football team, finds itself in this time of the year, every single year. And now I'm sad again.
		&lt;br&gt;
		&lt;br&gt;Life is short, and then you die.
		</text>
		<keywords>
			<keyword>clssroom</keyword>
			<keyword>thougths</keyword>
			<keyword>06</keyword>
			<keyword>6</keyword>
			<keyword>number</keyword>
			<keyword>writing</keyword>
			<keyword>bored</keyword>
			<keyword>university</keyword>
			<keyword>class</keyword>
			<keyword>joke</keyword>
			<keyword>serious</keyword>
			<keyword>arsenal</keyword>
			<keyword>classroom thoughts</keyword>
		</keywords>
	</item> 
 
	<item  id="classroom-thoughts-05">
		<date>
			<year>2016</year>
			<month>03</month>
			<day>31</day>
		</date>
		<title>Classroom Thoughts #05</title>
		<text>	
		The secret to success in life, to me, is to actually want the success. The most talented people that I've met have almost exclusively been slackers and under achievers, while their less talented peers have been miles ahead of them purely on hard work and dedication. As much as I love to jump on the bandwagon of system hate, the fact is that the lion's share of the blame has to go the person himself. This really is a shame because these are the people with the prowess to question the tried and the tested, to upset the apple cart, and to take the road less traveled, yet they settle to not taking any road at all. 
		&lt;br&gt;I had this thought while taking a bath, and I formulated it like this: "To succeed in life, you have to desire success more than you fear failure". I was really happy with the wordings and the idea, yet I was also sure that because it was such a generic and obvious thing to think, somebody must have already come up with it. A simple Google search confirmed my suspicion, the quote that I found was almost identical to mine, and was attributed to one Bill Cosby.
		&lt;br&gt;Whelp! Back to square one.
		</text>
		<keywords>
			<keyword>clssroom</keyword>
			<keyword>thougths</keyword>
			<keyword>05</keyword>
			<keyword>5</keyword>
			<keyword>number</keyword>
			<keyword>writing</keyword>
			<keyword>bored</keyword>
			<keyword>university</keyword>
			<keyword>class</keyword>
			<keyword>Deep Bullshit</keyword>
			<keyword>success</keyword>
			<keyword>secret</keyword>
			<keyword>life</keyword>
			<keyword>classroom thoughts</keyword>
			<keyword>education</keyword>
		</keywords>
	</item> 
 
	<item  id="classroom-thoughts-04">
		<date>
			<year>2016</year>
			<month>03</month>
			<day>30</day>
		</date>
		<title>Classroom Thoughts #04</title>
		<text>	
		Google DeepMind's AlphaGo AI has beaten legendary GO player Lee Sedol at it's own game. I do not say this lightly, but now is as good a time as there ever will be to say: Abandon Ship!
		&lt;br&gt;I will be watching my favorite apocalypse survival expert's documentary series for helpful tips and last minute brain waves. If only my crappy EVO "3G" would ever finish downloading the Terminator trilogy. And on that note, people keep pulling my leg, telling me there are actually more than three terminator movies. If I was so gullible, I would've fallen to the people who kept telling me of the two sequels to The Matrix. If these people had actually put in some effort into making up even a slightly believable and less ridiculous plot, I may just have fallen for it because of my undying love for the movie.
		&lt;br&gt;What irritates me the most about these people is that they don't even bother to sound convincing, You had to be there to actually appreciate the ridiculous plot these people came up with, for just thinking about me makes me sick to my stomach. Anyway, I digress, but you can't really blame for it. Not when I have just gone through the traumatic news that I have just shared. After all, who would be in there right mind after seeing the beginning of the machine uprising. 
		&lt;br&gt;Somebody shut down the bloody Skynet!
		</text>
		<keywords>
			<keyword>clssroom</keyword>
			<keyword>thougths</keyword>
			<keyword>04</keyword>
			<keyword>4</keyword>
			<keyword>number</keyword>
			<keyword>writing</keyword>
			<keyword>bored</keyword>
			<keyword>university</keyword>
			<keyword>class</keyword>
			<keyword>AI</keyword>
			<keyword>artificial</keyword>
			<keyword>intelligence</keyword>
			<keyword>robot</keyword>
			<keyword>classroom thoughts</keyword>
			<keyword>uprising</keyword>
			<keyword>Google</keyword>
			<keyword>DeepMind</keyword>
			<keyword>AlphaGo</keyword>
			<keyword>Go</keyword>
		</keywords>
	</item> 
  
	<item  id="classroom-thoughts-03">
		<date>
			<year>2016</year>
			<month>03</month>
			<day>29</day>
		</date>
		<title>Classroom Thoughts #03</title>
		<text>	
		I am no fan of the education system of my country. In fact, I have nothing positive to say about the system. I find i t counter-productive and the polar opposite of everything it is supposed to be.
		&lt;br&gt;But the worst thing, for me, about it is rather arbitrary and one that would not be most people's first pick. That problem is the sense of superiority and the self righteousness that our schools, colleges and universities instill in most of the students. Any half-decent, above average student thinks himself above the common folks, the riff raff that is far beneath their cultured and intellectual self. Education should be primarily focused on making people realize how much they don't know, rather than how much they do. I am under no illusion that the same thing is not true for most the world and their education system, yet I remain adamant that no country can equal the magnitude of the problem that we face.
		&lt;br&gt;To me, this is among the primary reasons for our plight and for the poverty of truly skilled professionals. After all, if you believe your own hype, you are highly unlikely to ever live up to it.
		&lt;br&gt;Now I fully realize that through this writing, I may be demonstration the very attributes that I am bemoaning, but what you have to understand is that I am writing from experience. I have been put on a pedestal most of my academic life by the teachers and by my peers just because I was above average and worked harder than most of the other students. As such, I know firsthand the damage this can do a child's learning curve, and had I not realized just how little I know, I may have been stuck in a bubble of self importance.
		&lt;br&gt;Although, seeing as how the self-awareness is working out for me, what do I know? Take everything i said with a pinch of salt, or with as much salt as you please.
		</text>
		<keywords>
			<keyword>clssroom</keyword>
			<keyword>thougths</keyword>
			<keyword>03</keyword>
			<keyword>3</keyword>
			<keyword>number</keyword>
			<keyword>writing</keyword>
			<keyword>bored</keyword>
			<keyword>lazy</keyword>
			<keyword>university</keyword>
			<keyword>class</keyword>
			<keyword>reflection</keyword>
			<keyword>self</keyword>
			<keyword>awareness</keyword>
			<keyword>deep bulshit</keyword>
			<keyword>classroom thoughts</keyword>
			<keyword>education</keyword>
			<keyword>system</keyword>
			<keyword>importance</keyword>
		</keywords>
	</item> 

	<item  id="classroom-thoughts-02">
		<date>
			<year>2016</year>
			<month>03</month>
			<day>10</day>
		</date>
		<title>Classroom Thoughts #02</title>
		<text>	
		I have come to the conclusion through reflection and self awareness, that everybody makes some presumptions on meeting anybody new based on the new guys looks, their get-up, their posture and their demeanor. This is perfectly normal and does not make a person prejudiced, what does it is to act out on those presumptions without giving the person a chance to challenge them, without getting  to know them, and without confirming those suspicions. I am not proud to say that I have caught myself judging people I did not know, more times than I would care to admit.
		&lt;br&gt; That is hardly an original thought and I am merely stating an observation that I found interesting. It is quite ironic that I am annoyed and enraged to wit's end at stereotypes the people apply on me, yet I have noticed that I do the same thing with people who have a similar outlook as mine. 
		&lt;br&gt;At this point I realize that I did not have sufficient time in the class to write out an adequate amount, so as to make a normal sized blog, so I just googled some quotes about prejudice to fill out the space. These three in particular caught my attention like no other. Though I have no idea if they actually belong to the people they are attributed to.
		&lt;br&gt;E. B. White
		&lt;div class="code"&gt;Prejudice is a great time saver. You can form opinions without having to get the facts.&lt;/div&gt;
		Mark Twain
		&lt;div class="code"&gt;The very ink with which history is written is merely fluid prejudice.&lt;/div&gt;
		Charles R. Swindoll
		&lt;div class="code"&gt;Prejudice is a learned trait. You're not born prejudiced; you're taught it.&lt;/div&gt;
		</text>
		<keywords>
			<keyword>clssroom</keyword>
			<keyword>thougths</keyword>
			<keyword>02</keyword>
			<keyword>2</keyword>
			<keyword>number</keyword>
			<keyword>writing</keyword>
			<keyword>bored</keyword>
			<keyword>lazy</keyword>
			<keyword>university</keyword>
			<keyword>class</keyword>
			<keyword>reflection</keyword>
			<keyword>self</keyword>
			<keyword>awareness</keyword>
			<keyword>deep bulshit</keyword>
			<keyword>classroom thoughts</keyword>
		</keywords>
	</item> 
  
	<item  id="classroom-thoughts-01">
		<date>
			<year>2016</year>
			<month>03</month>
			<day>09</day>
		</date>
		<title>Classroom Thoughts #01</title>
		<text>	
		Shower thoughts is a term I came  across while browsing &lt;a href="https://www.reddit.com"&gt;reddit&lt;/a&gt;, where it is a popular subreddit, for some reason, the term  stayed with me. I have recently started, or rather resumed, taking classes at my university after a hiatus, if you can call registering for the classes and missing most of them by being equal parts bored and lazy a hiatus. 
		&lt;br&gt;The boredom the classes cause are now two fold, as the classes are as dull and pointless as ever, but now I don't have people that I can talk with to make them bearable. But there seem to be an upside to the whole mess, as being bored out of my mind has spurred me into writing extensively, if aimlessly. I have written more in the first week back, than I had in the year and a half without the classes.
		&lt;br&gt;So to circle back to the first sentence, I will be posting these "writings" as Classroom Thoughts. Here is a taste of the all over the place mess, with some lines I wrote on my first day.
		&lt;br&gt;I am a great admirer of &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Satire"&gt;satire&lt;/a&gt;, especially Stephen Colbert's spin on it, which I think can be best described as caricature-esque satire. In trying to emulate the man, my results may be heavy handed, but as my first foray into the genre, I am quite content with them.
		&lt;br&gt;
		&lt;div class="code"&gt;It's good to be back taking classes. I am immensely enjoying it and have absolutely no urge to gouge my eyes out.&lt;/div&gt;
		&lt;div class="code"&gt;Hassan Nisar is brilliant, I try to follow him as much as I can. It is my staunch belief that Nisar is one of the only original thinkers this wretched country has ever produced. Incidentally, that is another thing me and Mr. Nisar can agree upon. I don't know what his qualifications or achievements are, but staying true to his style, I will just pretend that I do, and that they are unprecedented.&lt;/div&gt;
		&lt;div class="code"&gt;The purpose of our education seems to be, to put people off their studies, rather than to get them interested in them. Personally, I blame America,. First they stop us from getting quality education and producing good, productive professionals through the red blue and white force of television, movies and sponsored terrorism, not to mention deliberately causing earthquakes by bombing underground, than they swoop in to take away those who get good on their own. After all, how else can you explain the state of our education system. &lt;em&gt;Will you say we are not good enough?&lt;/em&gt; Yeah, didn't think so.&lt;/div&gt;
		</text>
		<keywords>
			<keyword>clssroom</keyword>
			<keyword>thougths</keyword>
			<keyword>01</keyword>
			<keyword>1</keyword>
			<keyword>number</keyword>
			<keyword>writing</keyword>
			<keyword>bored</keyword>
			<keyword>lazy</keyword>
			<keyword>university</keyword>
			<keyword>class</keyword>
			<keyword>satire</keyword>
			<keyword>comedy</keyword>
			<keyword>classroom thoughts</keyword>
		</keywords>
	</item>   
    
	<item  id="the-stop-and-chat">
		<date>
			<year>2016</year>
			<month>01</month>
			<day>29</day>
		</date>
		<title>The Stop and Chat</title>
		<text>	
		I am a student at a university about two hours of bus ride away from my home. I had been traveling to the university every day for three years, but it wasn’t going well at all. Not only am I extremely lazy, I also had to take the bus ride from hell every day. The road had gone to hell and the busses looked like they had gone a few rounds with a T-Rex, a few times during its wretched existence (yay! third world problems). I wasn’t allowed to take part in the last two semester finals, owing to my low attendance levels.
		&lt;br&gt;I finally had enough and got a hostel accommodation for the new semester. It's a two person room, so I had a roommate. I went down to the room, met with the roommate, we exchanged introductions and I moved in. 
		&lt;br&gt;Now, being an extreme case of social awkwardness, I do not do well with strangers and usually make do with nods and shakes of the head, and a few well timed hmm&lt;i&gt;s&lt;/i&gt;. I also avoided going to the room as much as I could, only going in to sleep and leaving early in the morning. I also left for home as soon as the final class of the week was done, and came back on the morning of the next one. Our conversations were limited to the exchange of pleasantries, and to me waking him up in the morning to have him close the door when I leave.
		&lt;br&gt;I was at home after about four months of this and my brother asked me to help out a friend of his friend who just got admitted, and needed help settling in to the university. As I wasn’t at the university I thought of asking the roommate to help the guy out. So I texted him and he agreed to help the guy out. When I was telling my brother about the guy who is going to help it dawned on me: I am not sure what the guy’s name is. I wasn’t sure if his name was “Hamad” or” Amaar”. I had saved his number as “Amaar” and had been calling him that for four months and he hadn’t corrected me, but I also recalled somebody calling him “Hamad”.
		&lt;br&gt;Told my brother I wasn’t sure between the two names, cue ridicule, he told his friend, cue ridicule &lt;i&gt;again&lt;/i&gt;. He told the friend in need. He met with the guy and told my brother his name was “Hamad”. 
		&lt;br&gt;I will not be living this one down.
		</text>
		<keywords>
			<keyword>stop</keyword>
			<keyword>chat</keyword>
			<keyword>the</keyword>
			<keyword>and</keyword>
			<keyword>social</keyword>
			<keyword>lazy</keyword>
			<keyword>socially</keyword>
			<keyword>awkward</keyword>
			<keyword>university</keyword>
			<keyword>roommate</keyword>
			<keyword>hostel</keyword>
		</keywords>
	</item>   
  
	<item  id="blank-page-syndrome">
		<date>
			<year>2015</year>
			<month>12</month>
			<day>10</day>
		</date>
		<title>Blank Page syndrome</title>
		<text>	
		I have loved reading for as long as I can remember. Being introverted, bordering on Sociopathic, I've always struggled with social interactions. I am perfectly happy sitting in awkward silence with a stranger, but for the life of me can not bring myself to engage in coversation. This means that I am, shockingly, not very popular even within my circle of acquaintances.
		&lt;br&gt;I found solace in reading, by virtue of it being something I can do on my own. Because of enjoying reading as much as I do, it only seems logical to think that I should be just as interested in writing. This is where I face a dilemma. I love writing, I want to write, and I would say, at the risk of coming across as big headed, that I am also quite good at it. The problem seems to stem from the fact that I am lazy as all hell, &lt;em&gt;and&lt;/em&gt; an idealist. I am, if you will forgive the cliché, my own biggest critic. Anything I write, or want to write, gets shot down immediately because it doesn't seem good enough.
		&lt;br&gt;All in all, I have a few blogs and a few lines of poetry to show for all the years of desire and attempt to write, not an impressive haul by any stretch of imagination.
		</text>
		<keywords>
			<keyword>blank</keyword>
			<keyword>page</keyword>
			<keyword>syndrome</keyword>
			<keyword>reading</keyword>
			<keyword>writing</keyword>
			<keyword>lazy</keyword>
			<keyword>idealist</keyword>
			<keyword>read</keyword>
			<keyword>write</keyword>
		</keywords>
	</item> 
  
	<item  id="thinking-out-loud">
		<date>
			<year>2015</year>
			<month>08</month>
			<day>14</day>
		</date>
		<title>Thinking out loud</title>
		<text>	The name of the blog was inspired by a rambling writing I wrote almost a year ago out of sheer boredom. I thought it would be fitting to publish it on the blog. This may make for a confused and purposeless reading, but if that is the case and you feel angry, you have only yourself to blame for expecting something better from a blog post on a blog that are both titled "Thinking out loud". And that is the last coherent thought you will read in this post:
				&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Life is not simple, it has more ebbs and flows then the "road" I take on the bus ride to the university everyday (the use of the word "everyday" being fairly liberal ).
				&lt;br&gt;There are times when I feel like I'm top of the world, like I have in me, the ability to do things other only dream of. Then there are times when my spirits sink lower than our educational standards.
				&lt;br&gt;I often wonder why I'm me and not someone else, often I get lost in dreams and then it's too late to get up for the class.
				&lt;br&gt;When the going gets tough and there seems to be nothing to look forward to, I stare at the disappointment crushing me into oblivion and remind myself, "Hey! there is football to look forward to this evening". So I play with all my heart, and pour my soul into it, returning home with a battered body but a refreshed mind. I feel great, apart from the smell of blood in my nose, and the aching knee that makes me feel like I'm sixty.
				&lt;br&gt;Being tired beyond reason works like a stimulant (I'm guessing), awakening the poet inside us, until it commits suicide after writing something like:
				&lt;br&gt;
				&lt;div class='code'&gt;
				Do you know, with what little understanding the world is ruled?
				&lt;br&gt;Just this, that people are sheep, only too willing to be fooled.
				&lt;/div&gt;
				&lt;br&gt;Another light at the end of the tunnel, another silver lining in the gloomy clouds is watching football. I've never known anything I enjoy quite as much as watching football (apart from playing it, of course). The sweet anticipation of watching your team in action again, which lasts only until I realize I support Arsenal, at which point I try to lower the expectation, mentally prepare for another potentially frustrating result, speculate which players I will get to watch getting injured this week, and start writing my heart out on a piece of paper. Because there are only so many things you can do when your father is sitting in front of your computer playing a video game that has no end.
		</text>
		<keywords>
			<keyword>thinking</keyword>
			<keyword>out</keyword>
			<keyword>loud</keyword>
			<keyword>inspiration</keyword>
			<keyword>origin</keyword>
			<keyword>8</keyword>
			<keyword>14</keyword>
			<keyword>2015</keyword>
			<keyword>august</keyword>
		</keywords>
	</item> 
  
	<item  id="urdu">
		<date>
			<year>2015</year>
			<month>08</month>
			<day>12</day>
		</date>
		<title>&lt;div class='urdu'&gt;اردو ہے جس کا نام&lt;/div&gt;</title>
		<text>	&lt;div class='urdu'&gt;مجھے پچپن سے ہی مطالعے کا شوق کسی بیماری کی طرح لگ گیا تھا، اس بیماری کی فطرت یقینی طور پر موروثی تھی، کہ میری والدہ کو بھی دنیا جہاں کی تحریریں پڑھنے کا خبط تھا۔
				&lt;br&gt;اسی عادت کی بناء پر میں نے چھوٹی عمر میں ہی بہت سے کتب پڑھ ڈالیں حتیٰ کہ چودہ پندرہ سال کی عمر میں تاریخِ اسلام کی ایک ضخیم کتاب کو بھی نہات ذوق و شوق سے پڑھ ڈالا۔
				&lt;br&gt;یہ تمام کتب اردو میں تھیں۔اردو سے اس خصوصی لگائو کی وجہ سے میری ہمیشہ سے خواہش رہی ہے کہ اردو میں کوئی اچھی سی تحریر لکھوں،مگر حالات کی ستم ظریفی ہے کہ آج تک 
				اردو میں کسی تحریر کو پایہِ تکمیل تک نہیں پہنچا سکا۔
				&lt;br&gt;اس بلاگ پرپہلی دفعہ انگریزی میں دو مضامین پر تحریریں ، صرف نظر اس سے کہ وہ کتنی ہی مختصر ہوں، لکھنے کے بعد مجھے شدت سے اس بات کا احساس ہوا کہ اپنی زبان
				کو چھوڑ کر اس زبان میں جو ناصرف کہ پرائی بلکہ بڑی حد تک اصول و مبادی سے آزاد ہے، تحریر کر کے مجھ سے بڑی فضول حرکت کا ارتکاب ہوا ہے ۔میرے نزدیک اس کا ازالہ
				کرنے کی واحد صورت یہ تھی کہ اردو میں بھی کم از کم ایک تحریر تو لکھ ہی ڈالوں،ہھر چاہے مجھے وہ کتنی ہی تھکی ہوئی اور بے ڈھنگی معلوم ہو۔
				&lt;br&gt;میں نے اکثراردو میں تحریر لکھتے ہوئے درپیش ذہنی رکاوٹ کی وجوہات پر غور کیا ہے اور میری نظر میں اس کی دو بڑی وجوہات ہیں۔
				&lt;br&gt;پہلی وجہ تو یہ ہے کہ اردو میں کسی حقیر سے حقیر موضوع پر لکھتے ہوئے بھی میں ہمیشہ اپنی تحریر کو اس بلند معیار پر پرکھنا چاہتا ہوں جس پر میرے پسندیدہ
				مصنفین نے تحریریں لکھی ہیں، اس کی وجہ سے یہ مصیبت پیش آتی ہے کہ کوئی تحریر کبھی اس قابل نظر ہی نہیں آتی کہ اس کو جاری رکھوں اور مکمل کر دوں۔
				یہ تحریر لکھتے ہوئے بھی کم از کم تین بار خیال آیا کہ اس خیال کو دماغ سے دھکے دے کر نکال دیا جائے اور آرام سے ایک تحریر انگریزی میں لکھ ماری جائے۔
				&lt;br&gt;دوسری وجہ جو مجھے محسوس ہوئی یہ ہے کہ ہمارے تعلیمی نظام کے اعلیٰ معیار کی وجہ سے ہماری حالت اس طرح کی ہے کہ بہت سے خیالات کے اظہار کے لیے 
				اردو کا کوئی مناسب لفظ نہیں ملتا اور مجبوراً دل پر جبر کر کے رومن اردو کی شکل میں انگریزی کا پیوند لگانا پڑ جاتا ہے۔ یہ چیز جہاں ایک طرف باعثِ شرم ہے وہیں
				غصہ دلانے والی بھی ہے اور کئی دفعہ تو صرف اس وجہ سے اچھی بھلی تحریر ردی کی ٹوکری کی نظر ہو جاتی ہے۔ اس تحریر کے لکھتے بھی لفظ بلاگ کا استعمال طوہاً و کرہاً کرنا پڑا۔
				&lt;br&gt;اس تحریر کی تکمیل کی وجہ صرف اتنی ہے کہ میرے ذہن میں کوئی موضوع نہ تھا اور تحریر مکمل کرنے کا عزم مضبوط تھا۔ 
				&lt;/div&gt;
		</text>
		<keywords>
			<keyword>اردو</keyword>
			<keyword>urdu</keyword>
			<keyword>writing</keyword>
			<keyword>8</keyword>
			<keyword>12</keyword>
			<keyword>2015</keyword>
			<keyword>august</keyword>
		</keywords>
	</item>  
  
	<item  id="marginal-problem">
		<date>
			<year>2015</year>
			<month>07</month>
			<day>05</day>
		</date>
		<title>Marginal Problem</title>
		<text>&lt;i&gt;"I have been careless, and so have been thwarted by luck and chance, those wreckers of all but the best-laid plans. But I know better now. I understand those things that I did not understand before."&lt;/i&gt;
				&lt;br&gt;In my last blog, I mentioned my knack of making clumsy and silly mistakes because of careless experimentation. I made the simplest and most problematic of mistakes a week or two ago, while making the home page of this web site. 
				&lt;br&gt;The problem occured while I was writing the javascript for my navigation bar. If you look at the navigation bar of my website you would see it snaps to the top once the user scrolls below it, a neat little trick that I really like. With the decrease in &lt;a href='http://www.w3schools.com/css/css_rwd_viewport.asp'&gt;viewport&lt;/a&gt; width, the nav bar's width adjusts automatically, a fixture of the responsive website elements.
				&lt;br&gt;I noticed that when I made the width smaller than a certain amount, the menu icon unexpectedly collapsed to the new line, a behaviour expected when the width of the element exceeds the remaining width on the line.
				&lt;img src='blog/margins-problem-1.png' alt='margins-problem-1.png'&gt; &lt;div class='caption'&gt;Pictured: Corrected nav bar, Not pictured: Hours down the drain&lt;/div&gt;
				&lt;br&gt;I spent hours upon hours trying to figure out what the problem was, as I had all the width's in percentages as opposed to fixed values, which should have stopped anomalies like this from arising their ugly little heads. I figured out the problem only after two days and many revisions of the code to try and find the problem, and figured out the problem: I had not bothered to read up properly on &lt;i&gt;&lt;b&gt;shorthand margin&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/i&gt; property in CSS, thinking it was too simple to misunderstand.
				&lt;div class='code'&gt; margin: top|right|bottom|right;&lt;br&gt;margin: top|bottom, left|right;&lt;br&gt;margin: top, right, bottom, left; &lt;/div&gt;
				Above are the valid forms of shorthand property I tried using, only I assumed the following syntax:
				&lt;div class='code'&gt; margin: top, right|bottom|left; &lt;br&gt; margin: top, right, bottom|left; &lt;/div&gt;
				Case in point, I was using the second of the two wrong properties. This caused an unwanted left margin on the menu bar icon, causing it to have larger width value than expected.
				I tracked it down using Firefox's DOM inspector, thankfully bringing and end to the most annoying and stressful debugging session I have had to go through, which coming from me, means a lot.
		</text>
		<keywords>
			<keyword>margin</keyword>
			<keyword>shortand</keyword>
			<keyword>css</keyword>
			<keyword>7</keyword>
			<keyword>5</keyword>
			<keyword>2015</keyword>
			<keyword>july</keyword>
		</keywords>
	</item>

	<item  id="first-blog">
		<date>
			<year>2015</year>
			<month>07</month>
			<day>04</day>
		</date>
		<title>First Blog!</title>
		<text>Finally got the blog setup completed, one step closer to finishing this site. The relief I feel is enormous and indescribable, starting and scraping countless web sites and web apps, I feared I would never be able to see anything through to the end. 
				&lt;br&gt; The blog is completely static, taking no help from back-end programming or a database. This means sacrificing security and flexibility for speed and simplicity (but is mainly down to the limitations posed by Neocities). &lt;br&gt;Shout out to Neocities for having an amazing service, and to the few hundred thousand people on sites like 
				&lt;a href='http://www.stackoverflow.com'&gt;Stack&lt;b&gt;Overflow&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/a&gt; for helping out with all the pointless mistakes I've made because of clumsy tinkering and adding bits of code without care.
		</text>
		<keywords>
			<keyword>first</keyword>
			<keyword>intro</keyword>
			<keyword>welcome</keyword>
			<keyword>7</keyword>
			<keyword>4</keyword>
			<keyword>2015</keyword>
			<keyword>july</keyword>
		</keywords>
	</item>
  
</items> 
